DIAA SAEB

Curriculum Vitae

PROFILE

Experienced information security specialist with a demonstrated penetration testing and digital forensics ability in actual cybersecurity incidents and responses, with the passion of exploit development field for testing and evaluating systems and applications. Skilled in System Administration and Database Management.

Each case has provided me with the opportunity to develop and sharpen the knowledge and expertise gained in fast-paced emergency settings, enabling me to stay productive and efficient.

WORK EXPERIENCE

<u>Aug 2019 – Apr 2020: Information Security Department Manager</u> Smart System Solutions (www.sss.sy), Damascus, Syria

Job Responsibilities:

- ♦ Assessing the risks to computer systems and planning to minimize possible threats.
- ♦ Upgrading existing security systems or designing new ones.
- ♦ Testing security products and evaluating them.
- Performing Vulnerability Assessment, Penetration Testing, and Digital Forensics for (Web - OS - Mobile App - Network).
- ♦ Managing and developing the information security team.
- ♦ Developing, maintaining and implementing information security policies, standards and procedures.
- ♦ Ensuring projects related to Information Technology infrastructure adhere to Security by Design principles.
- Participating in emergency response team activities for responding to various cyber-security incidents.
- Providing in-depth support for information security incidents including internal violations, cyberattacks, virus, and system outages.
- Preparing and periodically updating information security policies, architectures, standards, and/or other technical requirement or documents.

Jan 2009 – Sep 2018: Bug Bounty Hunter

Free Lance

<u>Jul 2014 – Aug 2014: IT Administrator</u> Akfali Group – IT Horizon, Damascus, Syria

Job Responsibilities:

- ♦ Upgrading and maintaining networks and systems for Clients.
- ♦ Providing support and troubleshoot.
- Upgrading and maintaining Software/Hardware.

Dummar Project, Island 11, Tower 1, Floor 6, Syria, Damascus.

Mobile: +963 (0) 94 99 42 554 E-mail: diasaeb@hotmail.com

DIAA SAEB

Curriculum Vitae

May 2013 – June 2013: ICT Teacher & Help-Desk Damascus Independent Academy, Damascus, Syria

Job Responsibilities:

- ♦ Upgrading and maintaining networks and systems .
- ♦ Teaching 6th, 7th, and 8th grades students Information and Communication Technology classes.

<u>June 2011 – Sep 2011: IT</u> Nasco Group – Nawar Sukkar, Deir Al-Zour, Syria

Job Responsibilities:

- ♦ Upgrading and maintaining Software/Hardware.
- ♦ Providing support and troubleshoot.

EDUCATION

♦ Bachelor's Degree of Electronics and Communications Engineering: 2011–2020: Damascus University, Syria. Graduation Project: Upgrading Smart Cities Based on IOT.

CERTIFICATES

- ♦ CEH: Certified Ethical Hacker, EC Council.
- ♦ NSE 1 & 2: Network Security Expert, Fortinet.
- ♦ Autopsy 8-Hour Training Course, Basis Technology.
- ♦ Industrial IOT on Google Cloud Platform, Google Support.

LANGUAGES

Arabic: Mother tongue.English: Excellent.

♦ French: Beginner.

PERSONAL DETAILS

♦ Name: Diaa Bassem Saeb
♦ Date of birth: 05/04/1993.

♦ Nationality: Syrian.

♦ Place of Residence: Syria, Damascus, Dummar Project

♦ Sex: Male.♦ Marital status: Single.

Dummar Project, Island 11, Tower 1, Floor 6, Syria, Damascus.

Mobile: +963 (0) 94 99 42 554 E-mail: diasaeb@hotmail.com